Guide to the Nicholas Georgescu-Roegen Papers, 1930-1994 RL.00442
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1930-1994 and undated; 1
  - Books, 3
    - The New Palgrave Dictionary correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 13)
    - The Promethean Destiny of Human Technology publisher correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 13)
  - Speeches, 4
    Assorted drafts of speeches, largely undated. Lecture notes and conference papers are found in the General Works subseries.
    - Miscellaneous speech ephemera, 1940s-1950s (Box 14)
    - Untitled anti-communist lecture, undated (Box 14)
    - Untitled lecture for Congregational Church re: life under communism, 1948 (Box 14)
    - Harvie Branscomb class talk, 1949 Dec. (Box 14)
    - Voice of America, 1967 June (Box 14)
- Econometrica/Econometric Society, 1949-1975; 2
  Materials largely center on Georgescu's work as an editor for Econometrica, including correspondence, drafts of various articles, and his comments on particular submissions. Includes his copies of the editorial correspondence surrounding Arrow-Debreu's article modelling a theory of general equilibrium.
  - Cowles Commission Discussion: Limitational Factors of Production and the Allocation of Resources, 1949 (Box 14)
  - Editorial correspondence and meeting discussions, 1952-1953 (Box 14)
  - Econometric Society Discussion: Production Control and Substitution session, 1953 Dec. 27 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence re: Arrow and Debreu's paper, Existence of an Equilibrium for a Competitive Economy, 1953-1954 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence re: Ando and Fisher article, 1961 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence re: G. Bernard's article, 1961-1962 (Box 14)
  - Editorial correspondence and meeting discussions, 1955-1968 (Box 14)
  - Symposium session on Pure Theory of Demand drafts, 1969 (Box 14)
  - Editorial correspondence with Franklin Fisher re: Fourastie's note, 1975 (Box 14)
- Biographical/Clippings, 1940s-1990s; 3
  This series contains an assortment of information about Georgescu, including both newspaper clippings and scholarly articles citing his economic work and his advocacy for Romania. The series also contains files documenting his various honorary degrees, a set of portraits of Georgescu, and various versions of his biography and curriculum vitae.
  - Autobiographical materials for dictionaries, directories, Who's Who, etc. (Box 14)
  - Curriculum vitae/resumes, various versions, 1975-1991 and undated (Box 14)
  - Photographs of NGR, undated (Box 14)
  - Honorary degree: Universite Louis Pasteur, Strasbourg, 1976-1977 (Box 14)
  - Honorary degree: Universita Degli Studi di Firenze, 1982 (Box 14)
  - Honorary degree: University of the South, 1982-1983 (Box 14)
  - Honors, miscellaneous, 1976-1990 (Box 14)
  - Clippings re: NGR, 1956, 1970s-1991 (Box 14)
  - Clippings, editorials re: NGR (Romanian), 1987-1990 (Box 14)
  - Articles citing NGR, 1965-1981 (Box 14)
  - Articles quoting NGR, 1980-1991 (Box 14)
- Teaching, 1950-1979; 4
  The Teaching Series contains lecture notes, syllabi, exams, and logistical correspondence from Georgescu's assorted teaching appointments in the United States and abroad between the 1950s and 1970s.
  - Introduction to Mathematical Economics, Vanderbilt (Econ. 526), 1950 and undated (Box 15)
  - Visiting professorship to Japan: Osaka and Hitotsubashi Universities, 1962-1963 (Box 15)
  - University of Sao Paolo/Ford Foundation, 1964-1971 (Box 15)
  - Course examinations, various, 1950-1976 (Box 15)
  - Ph.D. examinations, 1953-1967 (Box 15)
  - Economic Theory examinations, reading lists, 1965-1967 (Box 15)
  - Mathematics for Social Scientists syllabi, undated (Box 15)
  - Statistics assignments, notes, undated (Box 15)
  - Advanced Statistical Methods lecture notes, 1971-1972 (Box 15)
  - Romanian lectures on Optimalization, Mathematics, 1971 (Box 15)
  - Instituto de Pesquisas Economicas lectures, 1971 June (Box 15)
  - Visiting professorship: University of Texas at Austin, 1978-1979 (Box 15)
- Romania, 1944-1989; 5
  The Romania Series contains Georgescu's documentation from his service as a Romanian government official on committees relating to the Armistice and Soviet economic policy. Materials are loosely sorted and may need further arrangement. Languages include English and Romanian.
  - Romanian Commission for the Execution of the Armistice, 1944-1945 (Box 15)
  - Armistice Convention reports, 1944-1946 (Box 15)
  - Soviet/Romanian economic policies, agreements, 1944 and undated (Box 15)
  - Comisia Romana Pentru Aplicarea Armistitiului, 1945 (Box 15)
  - Romanian Economic Situation After the War, 1947 (Box 15)
  - Romanian/USSR economic policy studies, notes, undated (Box 15)
  - Romanian/USSR economic collaboration, 1945-1948 (Box 15)
  - Administratia Livrarilor, 1946-1947 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence/notes with Eduard Mark re: Office of Strategic Services, 1989 (Box 15)
- Research/Subjects, 1943-1990 and undated; 6
  This series includes an assortment of Georgescu's subject and research files, arranged by name or topic. A large portion of the series relates to Romania and its economy during the Cold War.
  - Additivity, 1960s-1980s (Box 16)
  - Chemistry, 1990 (Box 16)
  - Comics saved by NGR, undated (Box 16)
  - De Gleria, S., undated (Box 16)
  - Entropy (Palgrave), undated (Box 16)
  - Farm Surplus, 1965-1966 (Box 16)
  - Gamma Function, undated (Box 16)
  - Inflation, 1973 and undated (Box 16)
  - Kalecki, Michal, undated (Box 16)
  - Kekaumenos project, undated (Box 16)
  - Minerals/mining, 1977-1982 (Box 16)
  - Pareto, Vilfredo, undated (Box 16)
  - Philosophy, undated (Box 16)
  - Romania: General, undated (Box 16)
  - Romania: Authors, undated (Box 16)
  - Romania: Rumanian Culture and Behavior, by Ruth Benedict, 1943 (Box 16)
  - Romania: Communism, undated (Box 16)
  - Romania: Economic Reform, 1990 (Box 16)
  - Romania: Monetary System and Foreign Trade of Rumania, 1919-1952, 1953 (Box 16)
  - Romania: Notes by David John Hall, undated (Box 16)
  - Romania: Survey of Industrial Production in Communist Romania, by Brutus Coste, 1950 (Box 16)
  - Romania: History, undated (Box 16)
  - Schumpeter, Joseph, undated (Box 16)
  - Shaw, Lawrence, undated (Box 16)
  - Notes and quotations, unknown project, undated (Box 16)
  - Untitled notebook, undated (Box 17)
  - Various notes, untitled, undated (Box 17)
- Engagements, 1955-1992; 7
  The Engagement Series includes correspondence and logistical information documenting many of Georgescu's conference appearances, guest lectures, and tours at institutions around the world. Similar material also appears throughout the Correspondence series.
  - Visits/tours throughout Asia, 1962-1963 (Box 17)
  - Linear Programming Symposium, Washington, DC, 1955 Jan. (Box 17)
  - University of the South visit, Tennessee, 1966 (Box 17)
  - University of Alabama lecture, 1970 Dec. (Box 17)
  - Southern Economic Association conference, Miami, 1971 Nov. (Box 17)
  - University of Ghana visit, 1972 Mar. (Box 17)
  - Congress of the Institute: A Sociology for the Third World, Caracasa, Venezuela, 1972 Nov. (Box 17)
  - General travel correspondence, 1973-1976 (Box 17)
  - World Business Council meeting, St. Martin, 1973 Jan. (Box 17)
  - North Carolina State University/University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill lectures, 1974 Mar. (Box 17)
  - Sadi Carnot et L'Essor de la Thermodynamique roundtable, 1974 June (Box 17)
  - Western Michigan University lecture, 1974 Oct. (Box 17)
  - University of Missouri-Columbia lecture, 1975 Apr. (Box 17)
  - Patterson School Great Minds symposium, KY, 1975 Oct. (Box 17)
  - National Management Services conference, Touche Ross and Co., Atlanta, 1975 Nov. (Box 17)
  - University of Texas at Dallas symposium, 1976 Feb. (Box 17)
  - Western Michigan University lecture, 1976 Mar. (Box 17)
  - American Education Finance conference lecture, 1976 Mar. (Box 17)
  - Northern Illinois University lecture, 1976 Mar. (Box 17)
  - University of Wisconsin visit, 1976 Mar. (Box 17)
  - Haverford College lecture, 1976 Apr. (Box 17)
  - University of Utah visit, 1976 July (Box 17)
  - General travel correspondence, 1977 (Box 17)
  - London School of Economics lectures, 1977 May (Box 17)
  - Analysis and Dialectics in the Study of Evolution, at the University of Louis Pasteur, Strasbourg, 1977-1978 (Box 17)
  - General travel correspondence, 1978 (Box 17)
  - University of Oklahoma program, 1978 Feb. (Box 17)
  - First Seminar on Energy Planning, Caraballeda, Venezuela, 1978 Apr. (Box 17)
  - Brazil trip, 1978 Aug. (Box 17)
  - General travel correspondence, 1979 (Box 17)
  - Technical Congress for the Investigation and Conservation of Energy Resources, Puerto Rico, 1979 (Box 17)
  - General travel correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 17)
  - Ohio University visit, 1981 Feb. (Box 17)
  - Donald S. MacNoughton symposium, Syracuse University, 1981 Feb. (Box 17)
  - University of Calgary visit, 1981 Apr. (Box 17)
  - Thermodynamique et Sciences de L'Homme conference, Universite Paris-Val de Marne, 1981 June (Box 17)
  - Gordon Research Conference on Thermodynamic Analysis, 1981 June (Box 17)
  - General travel correspondence, 1982 (Box 17)
  - Institut fur Hohere Studien, Austria visit, 1982 (Box 17)
  - Science, Education, Evolution at the Centre for Human Evolution, Florence, 1982 (Box 17)
  - Beyond Psychology convention, American Psychological Association, 1982 Aug. (Box 17)
  - Dubrovnik International Conference (did not attend), 1982 Sept. (Box 17)
  - Energy in American History, Mountain Lake, Virginia, 1982 Oct. (Box 17)
  - Congress International des Economistes de Langue Francaise, Strasbourg, 1983 May (Box 17)
  - Third World Congress of Social Economics, Fresno, 1983 Aug. (Box 17)
  - Facing the Future: Atlantic Economic Society, Philadelphia conference, 1983 Oct. (Box 17)
  - General travel correspondence, 1985-1990 (Box 17)
  - Building Economics Workshop, National Science Foundation report, 1985 May (Box 17)
  - 14th International Conference on the Unity of the Sciences, Houston, 1985 (Box 18)
  - 15th International Conference on the Unity of the Sciences, Washington, DC, 1986 (Box 18)
  - Time and Economics conference, Hamburg, Germany, 1986 Apr. (Box 18)
  - Quels Fondements Epistemologiques Pour la Connaissance Economique? Colloquium, Mons, Belgium, 1987 Dec. (Box 18)
  - Environment and Development meeting, Milan, 1988 Mar. (Box 18)
  - Verdeuropa: Greens' International Convention, Florence, 1988 Oct. (Box 18)
  - Science, Technology, Economy: Engelberg forum, 1990 Mar. (Box 18)
  - Romanian Academy of Science induction, 1990 (Box 18)
  - Symposium on Thermodynamics and Energy Systems, ASME Conference, 1991 (Box 18)
  - Entropy and Bioeconomics conference, European Association for Bioeconomic Studies, Rome, 1991 Nov. (Box 18)
  - European Association for Bioeconomic Studies conference, Milan, 1992 (Box 18)
- Writings by Others, 1975-1994 and undated; 8
  The Writings by Others Series consists largely of unsolicited copies of articles and papers sent to Georgescu for comment. They have been arranged by author, and often include the accompanying correspondence. Similar material can be found in the Correspondence Series, also arranged by name. Georgescu's own research interests are also represented in this series, and his various colleagues and collaborators' work are also included.
  - Baranescu, George S., 1992 (Box 18)
  - Bartlett, Albert A., 1990 (Box 18)
  - Becker, Charles M., 1986 (Box 18)
  - Benvenuti, Giuliano, 1986 (Box 18)
  - Berg, Charles, 1987 (Box 18)
  - Berry, Stanley Keith, 1988 (Box 18)
  - Betancourt, Roger, 1985 (Box 18)
  - Bliss, Norman, 1985 (Box 18)
  - Bon, Ranko, 1988 (Box 18)
  - Bonauiti, Mauro, undated (Box 18)
  - Crivelli, Riccardo, 1987 (Box 18)
  - Cross, R.B., 1986 (Box 18)
  - Devchand, Vinodrai Maganlol, 1980 (Box 18)
  - Dopfer, Kurt, 1988 (Box 18)
  - Drago, Antonio, 1980-1982 (Box 18)
  - Elsenhans, Hartmut, 1994 (Box 19)
  - Erreygers, Guido, 1986 (Box 19)
  - Festshrift for NGR, 1975-1979 (Box 19)
  - Foster, John, 1992 (Box 19)
  - Gowdy, John, 1990 (Box 19)
  - Heertje, A., 1991 (Box 19)
  - Jenkins Colvin, Phyllis, 1975-1981 (Box 19)
  - Lozada, Gabriel, 1992 (Box 19)
  - Martinez-Alier, Juan, 1987-1991 (Box 19)
  - Mayumi, Kozo, 1988-1993 (Box 19)
  - Mehta, Nimai, 1994 (Box 19)
  - Mensch, Gerhard, 1981 (Box 19)
  - Misbra, S.S., undated (Box 19)
  - Moldau, Juan, 1993 (Box 19)
  - Muir, Tom, 1981 (Box 19)
  - Murota, Takeshi, 1991 (Box 19)
  - Naredo Perez, Jose Manuel, 1988 (Box 19)
  - Niedhart, James, undated (Box 19)
  - Romagnoli, Alessandro, 1987-1988 (Box 19)
  - Rosser, J. Barkley, 1989 (Box 19)
  - Rowley, Robin, and Omar Hamouda, 1988 (Box 19)
  - Rugina, Anghel, 1993 (Box 19)
  - Soderbaum, Peter, 1988 (Box 19)
  - Tani, Piero, 1988 (Box 19)
  - Todosia, Mihai, 1988 (Box 19)
  - Tomasson, Gunnar, 1990 (Box 19)
  - Van Daal, Jan, 1992 (Box 19)
  - Wagner, Douglas, 1983 (Box 19)
  - Wohlmuth, Paul, 1991 (Box 19)
  - Zencey, Eric, 1993 (Box 19)
- Correspondence, 1930s-1990s; 1
  NGR maintained an extensive correspondence not only with leading economists, but also physicists, engineers, and statisticians. There is correspondence with such luminaries as Wassily Leontief, Joseph Schumpeter, Paul Samuelson, Karl Pearson, and Friedrich Hayek. Also interesting is extensive fan mail from around the world, from people of various professions responding enthusiastically to his The Entropy Law and the Economic Process (1971) and Entropy: A New World View (1980), which found resonance with broader environmentalist and anti-growth sentiments. Institutional correspondence includes not only funding agencies but also work for many arms of the U.S. government (for instance, USAID, the CIA, the Department of Energy, various Senate committees, and Brookhaven National Laboratory) and important public intellectual platforms like the Club of Rome.
  Editorial correspondence from his work for Econometrica is filed in the Econometrica Series.
  - Name Files, 1
    - Accademia Nazionale dei Lincei, 1973-1976 (Box 20)
      Includes Congress on Vilfredo Pareto
    - Agency for International Development (Brazil), 1962-1973; 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Agricultural Development Council (Subsistence and Peasant Economics), 1963-1968 (Box 20)
    - Ahumado, Jorge, 1965 (Box 20)
    - Aigner, Dennis, 1972-1973 (Box 20)
    - Allred, John, 1976-1981; 3 folders (Box 20)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1973-1974, 1997 (Box 20)
    - American Agricultural Economics Association, 1971-1972 (Box 20)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1976-1982 (Box 20)
    - American Chemical Society (Chemrawn Conference), 1977-1979 (Box 20)
    - American Economic Association, 1970-1985; 2 folders (Box 20)
    - American Economic Review, 1966-1986 (Box 20)
    - American Institutes for Research in the Behavioral Sciences, 1975-1976 (Box 20)
    - American Romanian Academy of Arts and Sciences (ARA), 1967-1997; 3 folders (Box 20)
    - American Statistical Association, 1969-1971 (Box 20)
    - Andronescu, Serban C., 1990-1992 (Box 20)
    - Antoniu, Ion, 1975-1976 (Box 20)
    - Arrous, Jean, 1978-1982 (Box 20)
    - Arrow, Keneth, 1965 (Box 20)
    - Aschein, Joseph, 1974-1975 (Box 20)
    - Atlantic Economic Society, 1975-1984 (Box 20)
    - Atrill, Verne, 1973-1975 (Box 20)
    - Auster, Richard, 1973 (Box 20)
    - Avramescu (Family), 1966-1986 (Box 20)
    - Banco Nacional do Desenvolvimento Economico, 1972-1973 (Box 20)
    - Baranzini, Mauro, 1980-1991 (Box 20)
    - Barrier-Lynn, Christiane, 1983 (Box 20)
    - Battelle, 1975-1976 (Box 20)
    - Becattini, Giacomo, 1971-1986 (Box 20)
    - Benoit, Emile, 1974-1975 (Box 20)
    - Bender, Marilyn, 1974 (Box 20)
    - Benedetti, Carlo, 1966-1990 (Box 21)
    - Betancourt, Roger, 1982 (Box 21)
    - Bioscience Journal (regarding "The Steady State and Ecological Salvation"), 1976-1979 (Box 21)
    - Blang, Mark (re: Dictionary of Economists), 1981-1989 (Box 21)
    - Bonaiuti, Mauro, 1993-1994 (Box 21)
    - Boncher, William, 1979 (Box 21)
    - Boringhieri, 1979-1982 (Box 21)
    - Boserup, Mogens, 1977-1978 (Box 21)
    - Boulding, Kenneth, 1972-1981 (Box 21)
    - Bowman, David, 1990 (Box 21)
    - Bowonder, B., 1978 (Box 21)
    - Brahmananda, P. R., 1974 (Box 21)
    - Brantley, William, 1975-1979 (Box 21)
    - Bresso, Mercedes, 1983-1987 (Box 21)
    - Brinley, Thomes, 1973-1974 (Box 21)
    - Brodersohn, Mario, 1966-1967 (Box 21)
    - Bronfenbrenner, Martin, 1986 (Box 21)
    - Buchenan, James, 1986 (Box 21)
    - Buesco, Mercea, 1970-1991 (Box 21)
    - Bune, Mirko, 1975-1978 (Box 21)
    - Bunt, John S. (Australian Institute of Marine Science), 1979-1985 (Box 21)
    - Burch, Jr., William, 1972-1975 (Box 21)
    - Caldwell, Malcolm, 1975-1977 (Box 21)
    - Cantarelli, Davide, 1983-1985 (Box 21)
    - Carlson, Rey, 1967-1974 (Box 21)
    - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1965 (Box 21)
    - Center for Economic Education, 1979-1981 (Box 21)
    - The Center for Reflection on the Second Law, 1981-1991 (Box 21)
    - Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), 1982 (Box 21)
    - Cepede, M., 1966-1967 (Box 21)
    - Chabert, Alexandre, 1967-1982 (Box 21)
    - Chipman, John, 1969-1974 (Box 21)
    - Chirot, Daniel, 1971 (Box 21)
    - Clarendon Press, 1963-1976 (Box 21)
    - Clipea, Alexandru, 1972 (Box 21)
    - Cloud, Preston, 1973-1980 (Box 21)
    - Club of Rome, 1976-1983 (Box 21)
    - Cohen, Jacob, 1967-1968 (Box 21)
    - Cohendet, Patrick, 1983-1984 (Box 21)
    - Colander, David, 1991 (Box 21)
    - COMRATE - Committee of Mineral Resources and the Environment of the National Resources Center, 1973-1975 (Box 21)
    - Council for International Recreation, Culture, and Lifelong Education (CIRCLE), 1975 (Box 21)
    - Condruc, M., 1979-1980s (Box 21)
    - Crivelli, Riccardo, 1984-1990 (Box 21)
    - Dagum, Camilo, 1966-1976 (Box 21)
    - Dai Dong Conference, 1972-1975 (Box 21)
    - Daly, Herman, 1965-1993 (Box 21)
    - Daneke, Greg, 1980-1983 (Box 21)
    - Daniel, Sami, 1977-1986 (Box 21)
    - Dardi, Marcus, 1971-1977 (Box 21)
    - Das Gupta, K. K., 1979-1981 (Box 21)
    - Dasgupta, Dipankar, 1981 (Box 21)
    - Davis, Vincent (Lexington), 1975-1980 (Box 21)
    - Day, Richard H., 1968-1991 (Box 21)
    - Decei, Aurel, 1948-1949 (Box 21)
    - DeForest, J. D., 1973-1982 (Box 21)
    - De Gleria, Silvana, 1983-1986 (Box 21)
    - Dekker, Maurits (Marcel), 1975-1976 (Box 21)
    - Demetrescu, M.C., 1968-1994 (Box 21)
    - DiMarco, Luis, 1994 (Box 21)
    - Dix, Samuel, 1975-1976 (Box 21)
    - Dolloff, Norman M., 1975 (Box 21)
    - Dopfer, Kurt, 1984-1989 (Box 21)
    - Dragan, J. Constantin, 1979-1989 (Box 21)
    - Dorfman, Robert, 1979 (Box 22)
    - Dragnich, Alex, 1957-1990 (Box 22)
    - Drago, Antonino, 1981-1987 (Box 22)
    - Dubner, Howard, 1969-1970 (Box 22)
    - Dunod Editeur, 1969-1970 (Box 22)
    - Eastern Economic Journal, 1985-1986 (Box 22)
    - Earhart Foundation, 1966-1986 (Box 22)
    - Earth Metabolic Design, 1976-1977 (Box 22)
    - Ecole nationale superieure des telecommunications, 1976-1977 (Box 22)
    - The Ecologist, 1975-1980 (Box 22)
    - Economic History Association, 1975 (Box 22)
    - Ecoropa, 1980 (Box 22)
    - Edens, Thomas, 1975 (Box 22)
    - Edward Elgar Publishing, 1990-1993 (Box 22)
    - Ehrlich, Paul, 1975-1982 (Box 22)
    - English, J. M., 1973-1982 (Box 22)
    - Enzer, Hermann, 1966-1967 (Box 22)
    - Ercelawn, Aly Alp, 1969-1983 (Box 22)
    - Erickson, Edward, 1966-1967 (Box 22)
    - Eris, Ibrahim, 1970-1990 (Box 22)
    - ETAS Libri, 1979-1980 (Box 22)
    - European Association for Bioeconomic Studies (E.A.B.S.), 1991-1992 (Box 22)
    - European Association for Evolutionary Political Economy, 1991 (Box 22)
    - European Space Agency, 1980 (Box 22)
    - Faber, Malte, 1983-1986 (Box 22)
    - Fels, Rendings, 1962-1963 (Box 22)
    - Fiamboli, Gabriel, 1971-1975 (Box 22)
    - Fleckseder, Hellmut, 1975 (Box 22)
    - Federal Energy Administration, 1974 (Box 22)
    - Federal Trade Commission, 1974 (Box 22)
    - Feiwel, George, 1983-1984 (Box 22)
    - Fernandes, Santiago, 1965-1976 (Box 22)
    - Fitoussi, Jean-Paul, 1975-1984 (Box 22)
    - Flores, Edmundo, 1973-1978 (Box 22)
    - Foley, Vernart, 1975 (Box 22)
    - Foste, Wolfgang, 1986-1991 (Box 22)
    - Ford Foundation, 1974-1979 (Box 22)
    - Forscher, Frederick, 1975-1992 (Box 22)
    - Forum Engelberg, 1990-1991 (Box 22)
    - Fourastie, Jacqueline, 1975-1976 (Box 22)
    - Frankman, Myron, 1979-1980 (Box 22)
    - Friedman, Milton, 1973 (Box 22)
    - Friends of the Earth, 1975-1982 (Box 22)
    - Frisch, Ragnar, 1936 (Box 22)
    - Fulbright-Hays Award, 1973-1979 (Box 22)
    - Fundacao Getulio Vargas, 1967-1972 (Box 22)
    - Gale, Stephen, 1973-1979 (Box 22)
    - Gandolfo, Giancarlo, 1984-1988 (Box 22)
    - Garcia, Xavier, 1980-1981 (Box 22)
    - Ghosh, Sukosh K., 1974-1976 (Box 22)
    - Giarini, Orio, 1978-1979 (Box 22)
    - Grinewald, Jacques, 1974-1991 (Box 22)
    - Growth and Change journal, 1977-1979 (Box 22)
    - Guggenheim and Fulbright Foundations, 1957-1959 (Box 22)
    - Guitton, Henri, 1967-1981 (Box 22)
    - Gulf Research and Development Company, 1975 (Box 22)
    - Haberler, Gottfried, 1969-1972 (Box 22)
    - Hagemann, Harald, 1991-1992 (Box 22)
    - Hage, G. B., 1975 (Box 22)
    - Hall, Max (Harvard University Press), 1964-1974 (Box 22)
    - Hammer, Wolfgang, 1980-1984 (Box 22)
    - Hamouda, Omar, 1993-1994 (Box 22)
    - Hannon, Bruce, 1976 (Box 22)
    - Hardin, Garret, 1981 (Box 22)
    - Harvard University - Russian Research Center, 1948-1949 (Box 23)
    - Hatanaka, Michio, 1957-1991 (Box 23)
    - Hawk, David L., 1985 (Box 23)
    - Heertje, Arnold, 1991-1992 (Box 23)
    - Henderson, Hazel, 1975-1981 (Box 23)
    - Hesse, Gunter, 1985 (Box 23)
    - Hicks, John, 1973-1975 (Box 23)
    - Hoffman, George, 1971 (Box 23)
    - Hidalgo, Carlos, 1983-1984 (Box 23)
    - Hoffman, Nicholas von, 1974-1975 (Box 23)
    - Honkasalo, Antero, 1978-1983 (Box 23)
    - Houthakker, H. S., 1953 (Box 23)
    - Howell, Charles, 1982-1991 (Box 23)
    - Huddle, Donald, 1970-1975 (Box 23)
    - Hurwicz, Leonid, 1968-1971 (Box 23)
    - Iancu, Aurel, 1990-1993 (Box 23)
    - Indiana University Press, 1967-1975 (Box 23)
    - Instituto superior de agricultura, 1978-1980 (Box 23)
    - Interdisciplinary Science Reviews, 1976-1977 (Box 23)
    - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, 1972-1973 (Box 23)
    - International Economic Association, 1965-1969 (Box 23)
    - International Federation of Institutes for Advanced Study (IFIAS), 1975-1978 (Box 23)
    - International Institute of Sociology, 1963-1974 (Box 23)
    - International Journal on the Unity of the Sciences, 1985-1987 (Box 23)
    - International Society for the Study of Time, 1979-1980 (Box 23)
    - International Statistical Institute, 1966-1974 (Box 23)
    - Jaffe, William, 1972-1975 (Box 23)
    - Jenkin, Michael Phyllis, 1975-1982 (Box 23)
    - Johnson, Harry G., 1964-1967 (Box 23)
    - Journal of Economic Issues, 1972-1981 (Box 23)
    - Journal of Economic Literature, 1972-1976 (Box 23)
    - Junker, Louis, 1977-1981 (Box 23)
    - Kapp, William, 1975 (Box 23)
    - Katzner, Donald, 1973-1974 (Box 23)
    - Koide, Kounosuke, 1977-1994; 4 folders (Box 23)
    - Koyama, Naokuni, 1978-1981 (Box 23)
    - Kuenne, Robert, 1965-1974 (Box 23)
    - Kuznets, Simon, 1971 (Box 23)
    - Lari, Eugenio, 1983 (Box 23)
    - Laudadio, Leonard, 1973-1975 (Box 23)
    - Lepkowski, Wil, 1974-1979 (Box 23)
    - Leontief, Wassily, 1948-1974 (Box 23)
    - Lior, Noam, 1991-1992 (Box 23)
    - Lombardo, Heraclio, 1965-1967 (Box 23)
    - London, James, 1983-1984 (Box 23)
    - Long, Richard, 1967-1973 (Box 23)
    - Lopez-Solorzano, Joaquin, 1981-1987 (Box 23)
    - Lowe, Adolphe, 1968-1973 (Box 23)